

MARTIN KARIUKI

Quality, Environment, Health and Safety Professional

A highly motivated and ambitious individual able to give timely and accurate advice, guidance, support, and training to team members and individuals. Possessing excellent management skills and having the ability to work with the minimum of supervision. Having a proven ability to lead by example, consistently hit targets, improve best practices and organize time efficiently. I am also certified and licensed by NEMA as an Environmental Impact Assessment/ Environmental Audit Expert (Reg. No. 8583)

□ +254781888815 🖂 mkariuki500@gmail.com

3rd of September 1990

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 - Present

Chief of Staff to the Chairman GulfCap Africa and Kenya Trade Network Agency (KenTrade)

As chief of Staff, I provide support to the Chairman in administration, project management, financial management, strategy, communications, public relations, human resource management, advisory, proxy, relationship management, and gatekeeping.

GulfCap Africa is a Private Equity Company with founding investments in Gulf African Bank, Gulf Energy, Gulf Power, Gulf Homes, Amu Power, Proposed Coast International University and many other companies internationally.

Kenya Trade Network Agency (KenTrade) is a State Corporation under the National Treasury established in in January 2011 to establish, implement and manage the National Electronic Single Window System (KenyaTradeNet System) and to facilitate trade. Kenya TradeNet System is an online platform that serves as a single entry point for parties involved in international trade and transport logistics to lodge documents electronically, for processing, approvals and to make payments electronically for fees, levies, duties, and taxes due to the Government, on goods imported or exported in the country.

2018 - Present

Director, Business Development Reynard Africa Limited

Reynard Africa is the sole distributor of Herman Miller furniture in East and Central Africa. Herman Miller, Inc., based in Zeeland, Michigan, is an American company that produces office furniture, equipment, and home furnishings.

Achievements

Creativity, negotiating and networking skills made the company allocate me the responsibility of also leading the sales and marketing team.

I was tasked with the responsibility of developing Quality, Health, Safety & Environment policy, and management systems for the company and oversee the implementation.

★ REFERENCE

2017 - 2017

Personal Assistant to Hon. Suleiman Shahbal Mombasa County Gubernatorial Candidate

Working in a fast-paced environment, giving full administrative, personal, secretarial, research and political support

services to the candidate which include: * Supervising the Governor's Delivery Unit (GDU) encompassing paid and volunteer support staff * Managing the diary, updating databases, arranging meetings, conducting research and helping the candidate write speeches * Briefing the candidate on urgent issues and other matters of interest * Management of

Health & Safety issues.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Developed and Implemented a campaign schedule that made the team meet 100% of all the groups in the community that had been set as a target, within the anticipated time and budget.

2015 - Present 4 YEARS, 4 MONTHS

Environment, Health and Occupational Safety Consultant Prinsafe Consult

Prinsafe Consult is an Environment and Occupational Safety Consultancy Firm.

Achievements:

As a part-time consultant, I have been able to work with various companies in different sectors on Occupational Safety, Environment, and Research.

I have successfully consulted on the following areas; conducting risk assessments, developing OSH and Environment Management System, Writing policy documents, developing emergency Management Plan, Conducting Environmental Impact Assessments and Audits.

I have also been actively involved in carrying out a feasibility study on setting up plastic pyrolysis plants in Kenya as an alternative source of oil and a way of managing plastic waste in various counties.

Some of the clients I have consulted for include; Indigo Energy Kenya, Satique Construction Company, Duff Engineering, Chummer Limited, Elhamzy Transporters, Cargill and EMERC Construction Company among others.

2014 - 2017 3 YEARS, 5 MONTHS

Administration Manager Coast International Limited (CIL)

CIL is the sponsor of Proposed Coast International University.

Responsibilities include *Managing Quality, Environment, Health, Safety and Security (QEHSS) function of the institution *Directing, planning and coordinating essential support services such as reception, maintenance, mail, archiving, cleaning, catering, transport, waste disposal and recycling *Managing support staff, contractors, and other service providers *Preparing and managing administrative budgets

ACHIEVEMENTS

- *Supervised Refurbishment of facilities for establishment of CIU *Prepared all Quality, Health and Safety Policy documents for the company
- *Introduced highly successful streamlined auditing, incident reporting, and risk assessment processes, creating a standardized approach to safety
- *Trained all employees on OH&S practices and legal obligations at induction and ongoing basis

2014 - 2014 8 MONTHS

Projects Officer Reynard Africa Limited (RAL)

RAL is an interior design company and the sole distributor of Herman Miller office furniture in East and Central Africa

Responsibilities include; *Sourcing for new clients and follow-up on existing ones *Project identification, monitoring of implementation and appraisal *Preparing tender documents *Preparing Quotations *Preparing Marketing Presentations, *Support the administrative and logistical arrangements for the implementation of program activities.

Increased the company's sales and clientele base by more than 20% within the first four months of employment. I achieved this through the introduction of Digital Marketing and preparation of persuasive presentations for our prospective clients.

2013 - 2014 8 MONTHS

Medical Writer Medivizor International Limited (www.medivizor.com)

Medivizor provides people with severe or chronic medical conditions all the cuttingedge information they need know - personalized just for them

RESPONSIBILITIES

Responsibilities include; *Rewriting and summarizing scientific journal articles into 350 words simple-English article through extensive research *Assessing credibility of the research findings

EDUCATION

2018 -	2018
1 MONTH	

Complete Health and Safety Auditor Course. OHSAS 18001 Udemy Online

How to implement and audit a health & safety management system and obtain certification to OHSAS 18001 Standard.

2018 - 2018 1 MONTH

ISO 14001:2015 Environmental management system Course Udemy Online

How to implement an Environmental Management System and obtain ISO 14001:2015 certification.

2017 - 2017

Business Management & Entrepreneurship Course Alison Online

Modules Covered Include;

- *Project Management
- *Operations Management
- *Corporate Management
- *Introduction to Human Resources Management
- *Fundamentals of Accounting
- *Fundamentals of Financial Accounting
- *Stone Soup Starting a Business or Social Enterprise

2017 - 2017 1 MONTH

ISO 9001:2015 Quality Management System (Fundamental Concepts)

COURSE Alison Online

Module include:

- *Foundations of Quality Management System
- *Essential Elements of Quality Management System

2015 - 2018 3 YEARS, 1 MONTH	Master of Science in Occupational Safety and Health Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture & Technology Ongoing (Thesis Stage)
2010 - 2013 3 YEARS, 8 MONTHS	Bachelor of Technology Industrial Microbiology and Biotechnology Technical University of Mombasa Second Class Honors (Upper Division)
2004 - 2008 4 YEARS, 1 MONTH	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Teremi Boys High School A (Minus)

★ SKILLS



LANGUAGE SKILLS

Swahili English
spoken: fluent
written: fluent
written: fluent

HOBBIES

Social Networking Swimming

ASSOCIATIONS

Environment Institute of Kenya associate expert

Technical University of Mombasa Students' Organization secretary general (2011/2012)

Teremi Boys High School Prefects Body SCHOOL CAPTAIN (2008)

REFERENCES

Caroline Mutua Manager, Reynard Africa Limited February 2019

□ +254724507858 🖂 hr@reynardafrica.com

Martin Kariuki is team player, very proactive and a wonderful sales person. We are honored to have him re-join the team. A combination of his peoples skills, desire to learn, versatility, team leadership and problem solving skills makes him an asset to the company.